The moment has arrived.
드디어 때가 왔어요
Here we go.
시작할게요
We're in fine tuning.
잘 조정하고 있어요
We do fine tuning.
세세한 조율을 하죠
Train.
기차요
There is also a line here to push it to the hub after it's finished.
작업이 끝나면 허브에 넣는 라인도 있어요
Let's kick that off.
시작해 보죠
So while it's kicking off, we'll take a quick look.
시작되는 동안 잠깐 살펴보죠
The GPU is starting at six, which is what we expect.
GPU 시작점이 6점이에요 예상 수치죠
It's about as much as it needs for the the model itself.
모델 자체에 필요한 건 다 있어요
And it's going to be warming itself up and getting ready for this training while it's doing that.
그걸 하는 동안 몸을 데우면서 훈련을 준비하죠
Since we're waiting for it just for a second, I might as well just talk to some of these other training
기다리고 있으니 다른 훈련 매개 변수들에 대해 얘기할게요
parameters that we that we didn't mention before.
전에 언급하지 않은 것들이죠
Um, eval strategy.
평가 전략요
So it is typical when you're doing this kind of training that you would repeatedly have a held out data
이런 종류의 훈련을 할 때 전형적으로 지속적으로 데이터 세트를 갖고 평가할
set that you would use for evaluation, that you would use as a constant set that's not involved in
겁니다 훈련에 포함되지 않은 상수 집합으로 사용할 거예요 모델이
training, that you would use to get the model to, uh, validate that it's making progress.
진전을 이루고 있는지 유효성을 검사하기 위해 사용하겠죠
Now, I've not done that here.
여기선 안 해봤어요
Um, partly because we've got so much training data that I think it's got plenty to be training on.
훈련 데이터가 너무 많아서 훈련할 게 많은 것 같아요
Um, just in one epoch alone and and partly because I just performance, the speed of training was so
한 시대에서만요 그리고 공연 때문이기도 하지만 훈련 속도가 정말 중요했어요
important.
이걸 통해 반복적으로 유효성 검증을 하는 걸 멈추고 싶지 않았어요
But it is a best practice to have a validation data set.
유효성 검증 데이터 모음이 최선의 관행이죠
We've got plenty of data for it.
데이터는 충분히 있어요
We we held out 2000 test data points so you can use a bunch of them, um, as part of your validation
2,000개의 테스트 데이터 포인트를 개최해서 그중 다수를 사용할 수 있습니다 유효성 검사
step uh test test set.
단계인 테스트 세트로요
So one certain improvement to this, that would be more of a best practice would be to use an eval strategy
개선점을 찾자면 최선의 관행은 평가 전략을 활용해서 훈련 데이터와 함께 유효성
and pass in validation data as well as training data.
검증 데이터를 통과하는 거죠
Um, but but it wasn't a super necessary in this case, so I didn't do it.
하지만 이 경우에는 꼭 필요한 건 아니라서 안 했어요
Um, okay.
네
Well, you may notice if you are glancing over this way that the GPU memory has shot up and out of the
이 쪽으로 보면 GPU 메모리가 40GB 밖으로 나왔고 제가 가진
40GB of GPU memory that I've got, 38.2 is currently being used.
GPU 메모리에선 38GB가 나왔죠 현재 2를 사용하고 있어요
So I really did squeeze this so that, uh, with 16 batch steps, uh, a batch size of 16, I would
16개의 배치 단계가 있고 배치 사이즈는 16입니다 GPU 전체를 거의 다
really use up almost the entire GPU, very close to running out there and you can see that stuff is
사용하게 됩니다 실행되는 것과 비슷합니다 여기에서 일어나는 일을
happening down there.
볼 수 있죠
So let's just, uh, scroll down and see what we're seeing here.
스크롤을 내려서 뭐가 보이는지 보죠
Um, so it's off and running and we can see that that things are happening.
작동 중이고 어떻게 되는지 볼 수 있어요
Uh, and now to run the entire three epochs is going to take, uh, according to this estimate here,
이제 세 개 개국을 다스리는 데 24시간 정도 걸릴
uh, just over 24 hours.
거예요
26 hours or so.
26시간 정도요
Uh, so, you know, it is something like eight hours per epoch, um, on this, uh, even on this beefy
개혁기마다 8시간 정도 작업합니다 이 육중한 기체도 마찬가지입니다 훈련 데이터가
machine, because the training data is so enormous, but it's not strictly necessary to go through all
방대하긴 하지만 400,000개의 훈련 데이터를 전부
400,000, uh, training data.
검토할 필요는 없거든요
And as I say, you can run this on a much lower end box and let it run for for a while, and that is
말씀드렸듯이 훨씬 낮은 버전의 박스에서 실행할 수 있고 한동안 실행하게 둘 수도 있어요
all completely fine.
그건 다 괜찮아요
Um, but what you're seeing here is it's it's it's off every 50 steps, just as we configured.
하지만 여기서 보시는 건 50단계마다 달라요 우리가 구성한 대로요
We're getting an output that shows us our training loss so far.
지금까지의 훈련 손실을 보여주는 결과가 나오고 있어요
Um, and this is now running and outputting to weights and biases.
지금은 무게와 편향성을 측정하고 있어요
And in the next video, I will give you a peek into how that's looking.
다음 영상에서는 어떻게 생겼는지 살짝 보여드릴게요